{
  "id": 401,
  "themeId": 4,
  "name": "Writing and Reading Singular/plural – Quiz 1",
  "description": "Practice Singular and Plural vocabulary and grammar through writing and reading exercises.",
  "version": "2.2.3",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "How do you say "tests"?",
      "options": ["A. Les tests", "B. Les testes", "C. Les textes", "D. All of the above"],
      "correctAnswer": "A. Les tests"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"chocolates\"?",
      "options": ["A. Les chocolats", "B. Les chocolatx", "C. Les chocolates", "D. Les chocolatex"],
      "correctAnswer": "A. Les chocolats"
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say "arms"?",
      "options": ["A. Vos bras", "B. Tes bras", "C. Les bras", "D. All of the above"],
      "correctAnswer": "C. Les bras",
      "explanation": "When a noun ends with S like bras, the ending does not change when plural."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say "countries"?",
      "options": ["A. Les payes", "B. Les pays", "C. Les payent", "D. Les payies"],
      "correctAnswer": "B. Les pays",
      "explanation": "When a noun ends with YS like pays, the ending does not change when plural."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say "birds"?",
      "options": ["A. Les oisox", "B. Les oises", "C. Les oiseaux", "D. Les oiseaus"],
      "correctAnswer": "C. Les oiseaux",
      "explanation": "When a noun ends with EAU, it ends with an X when plural. There are exceptions like landeau (landaus/baby carriages)."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say "kisses"?",
      "options": ["A. Les bisoux", "B. Les bisous", "C. Les bisoûs", "D. Les biso'us"],
      "correctAnswer": "B. Les bisous",
      "explanation": "Nouns ending in OU take an S when plural. There are exceptions like poux (lice), bijoux (jewels), chous (cabbages), genous (knees), etc."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"lice\"?",
      "options": ["A. Les pouxes", "B. Les pouxs", "C. Les pous", "D. Les poux"],
      "correctAnswer": "D. Les poux",
      "explanation": "Nouns ending in OU take an S when plural. There are exceptions like poux (lice), bijoux (jewels), chous (cabbages), genous (knees), etc."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"hair\"? (plural)",
      "options": ["A. Les chevaux", "B. Le cheveu", "C. Les cheveus", "D. Les cheveux"],
      "correctAnswer": "D. Les cheveux",
      "explanation": "When a noun ends with EU, it ends with an X when plural. There are exceptions like bleu (bleus/bruises)."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"plants\"?",
      "options": ["A. Les plants", "B. Les plantx", "C. Les plantes", "D. Les planteux"],
      "correctAnswer": "C. Les plantes",
      "explanation": "Nouns ending with an E like plante (plant) take an S when plural."
    },
    {
      "question": "How do you say \"kids\" ?",
      "options": ["A. Les enfants", "B. Les enfantes", "C. Les enfantx", "D. All of the above"],
      "correctAnswer": "A. Les enfants",
      "explanation": "Nouns ending with a consonant will take an S when plural."
    }
  ]
}